Right.
Just kind of blobs.
Yeah, yeah.
But he can be taller sometimes than others, right?
Yeah, he's got pods sticking up.
I mean, maybe that's you know, fake eyeballs.
With Glabbagool standing protectively over his fallen body, Thorin engaged his interim thugs directly, striking one with Dawnbringer and using menacing attack, though the hardened thug resisted the psychological presser.
Grygum surge forward and unleashed Tasha's caustic burr, coating both of thugs and acids.
One died instantly as the corrosive Blu-ru melted him, and the other stood soaked in acid, the session ending with a battle still raging.
I mean, it's a pretty mean thing to do, but I did it anyway.
Throw acid on somebody.
Well, actually, what you did was you barfed.
Strictly speaking, the mechanics of Tasha's caustic acid group is you barf.
I need to go back and reread the description.
I maybe didn't know that, Costas.
Maybe I'll have to swap that out for another spell.
What is it?
Described.
All right.
There we go.
There's a.
All right.
I have to find it, but there's a website that has D and D content written by writers so that you can have full descriptions.
That's for sale.
In this era of AI work, it actually is even more valuable because it doesn't sound like it was written with claws.
All right.
So let me get it.
So just in case, Gabe, just in case you, the thing that you missed was after defeating the
metal constructs, you talked, you guys, my wife, Pauline, yeah.
Did we level up?
Let me see.
What level are we?
We did level while you were out, Gabe.
I think.
I'm level 9 now.
Are you level 9?
Yeah, I guess Costas levels for me.
That's exciting.
Maybe.
Yeah, level 9.
Right.
Sorry.
All right.
Where is it?
I'm trying to figure something out.
Yes.
Roll 20.
That's what I was looking for.
Right.
So, Gabe, sorry.
You defeated the monsters.
After you defeated the monsters, you discovered that the key you had was a fake.
Which of the keys was fake?
The one from the one that you guys had.
From way back when the card guy gave us?
Yes, Kalan actually gave you a fake key.
Yeah, because there was like detect magic and it didn't glow, and you're like, what up with that?
Yeah, and it turns out that's why all your magic spells weren't working because it was just a plain old vanilla key.
Right?
And so, Kalan, and so when Kalan, when you asked Kalan what happened, he admitted that he was using you guys as a distraction from where the real key was.
And then he told you where the real key was, and it was on Tadric.
You rushed over there and then managed to kill him in one round, much to my irritation, forcing me to redo a large amount of the remainder of the adventure.
Oh, no.
Seems normal.
Yeah, just for the record, I was like, well, we do our best to screw up your plan.
No, no, no.
I even said, I even did my prep.
I said, this is going to be unlikely.
I don't like no.
This is proof that I don't railroad.
There's no railroading, even if the GM has to spend overnight rewriting everything.
I'm sorry.
You have helped me.
No, you shouldn't feel sorry, dude.
You don't get you doing it.
You're not doing that.
This is me humble bragging.
I'm sorry.
In my other campaign, the players were kind of fed up with the adventure and they wanted it to end.
And so I have rewrote the entire ending.
Did they want to start a new adventure or they were just tired of hanging out together?
No, no, no.
They wanted to start a new adventure.
The adventure had gone on for a little bit longer than any of us wanted it.
It's like we're done with this.
Yeah, no, they were kind of done with it.
Like, we'd be done.
So we ended it.
It ended in a, I actually think the ending we came up with was a lot better.
All right.
So just to make sure you know what the, so, so, yeah, so you've arrived.
You're unconscious, Gabe.
Why are you unconscious?
Because, well, quite honestly, I couldn't figure out how to play your character.
Just to be clear, the Roll 20, the AI said, why didn't he do this, this, and this?
And I had to tell it because I was playing him and didn't know how to play them up.
And then it said, okay, that tracks.
Or something along those signs.
Just for the record, yes, you died because I screwed up.
Fair enough.
I mean, there's a lot of tools to this character.
Yes, I shadow stepped instead of using his movement speed to cross the distance, thus blowing the bonus attack.
That's fair.
So you're going to wrap on things?
Are we going to fix it?
No, I mean, you still, just to be clear, I did the math.
He still wouldn't, Alay still wouldn't be dead.
I have all kinds of resurrection spells.
Right.
And, you know, poor Glabbagool forgot to do his damage.
So my point is: Glabbagool is available to you.
All right.
That is Glabbagool.
Okay.
And I think the last thing we did.
So we've solved everything, and I've lost your.
No, so it's actually just the thug who's, yes, you're in the middle of combat.
Ah, okay.
All right.
So just so you all know, Manshoon is a legendary figure.
That's the point you're supposed to derive from the fact that you would have heard of him.
Ah.
But he's unrelated to our current fight.
Well, except for the fact that, so just because there's a bit of lore items that those of us who've been playing this game for too long know too well.
One, in Candlekeep, it's impossible to steal a book, and yet somehow somebody's been stealing books for the last 11 years.
That's literally social engineering.
They're the person who keeps track of the books.
But, well, apparently, if you've got an avowed who's one of the leaders of the whole thing in your back pocket, and you've got the right magical artifact, anything is possible.
Yeah, it reminds me of somebody who was working on a project we needed at another company, and he would sneak in commits for us occasionally when it was important by turning off the email notification that told people that a commit had been done.
Should this be recorded?
This was decades ago.
Okay, statue limitations is done.
How much?
And you just heard about this third hand, and you were not involved in it.
And that's what was going on, right?
I mean, it was over a beer in Palo Alto.
Yeah, you heard the story about this co-worker, you were not involved in any of it, right?
And you don't care because this was on Citrix Zen server.
Anyway, I'm going to keep going.
So, yes.
So, yes, and so the first rule of magical defenses is there's always a way around a magical defense.
Yeah, you have a more specific magic to get around it.
Exactly.
So, first of all, so Candlekeep is the property that nobody can steal books.
So, walking into a place and seeing a whole bunch of people stealing books is kind of mind-boggling.
Right?
So, that's one piece of lore.
My mind-boggles at it.
Yeah, I know.
Stealing books, why would you steal books, right?
And this is why the whole thing where, you know, getting a book from Candlekeep is a big deal.
Have they ever considered just copying the books?
Yes.
Imagine there's some DRM on some of these books, magical books.
I mean, yeah, I mean, they've thought about copying these books, but it's not clear how that would produce a good paper.
Oh.
I'm sure there's a program dedicated to coming up with automated mechanisms of doing that, but that presearch program didn't go anywhere.
Well, maybe it's hard to copy magic books.
Yeah.
So anyway, so yeah, so they have.
So the first thing is they have, it's a place where all the books are, you can't steal books.
So the first thing that's really weird is how the hell were books being stolen.
The second thing that's important is that the place has a force field, right?
And here there are bad guys inside.
So whatever mechanism somebody was using to get the books could bring the bad guys in too.
May have brought the bad guys in, right?
And the third thing is that the third piece of lore.
Okay, Manchoon.
So Manchoon, so the Zentarim are, you know, have gone through, this is a meta critique.
The Zentarim have gone through every bad decision of the Dungeons and Dragonkins community over the last 30 years.
But they were originally founded by this guy, by this one group, and then Manshoon tooks over, and Manshoon decides to go turn them into an evil cult of ball.
He's eventually killed, but because this is, you know, comic book villain, he can't die, so he keeps coming back in all different possible ways.
Right.
So he's a very powerful wizard who keeps showing up over and over again.
He's like the ultimate bad Benny.
And every time he shows up, it's not like, you know, a teleporter mistake where he turns into a good guy, like everybody's favorite Kenku.
Where he became a Weir Bearer, was it?
Yeah, Weirbear, and then literally did you know that that turns him good?
Who knew?
Right?
So, yes, he certainly didn't beforehand.
No.
But he had such good tutelage from Milo Goodbarrel and rationalizations.
Exactly.
You don't steal everything.
You steal enough to cover appropriate expenses, operational overhead, a reasonable salary.
Supplies or whatever.
Yeah, supplies.
There's like thieves and then there's politicians.
And they're the same.
They just have different names.
This makes me wonder what we can justify to our VCs after the Series A.
We'll get my little.
My wife just texted me.
Did I tell you guys?
I don't know, last week or the week before?
Yeah, you told us about the Series A.
Yeah, it closed.
We got the money.
So it's exactly the same.
I celebrated that.
I mean, I don't know if Gabe heard that, but yes.
And you were also saying that with the revenue you have coming in and everything else, it sounds like this might be the last time you have to raise.
I don't know how that we don't know, but we've got revenue.
All right.
So let's go.
So just so we're on the same page.
All right.
So, Daz, I'm assuming you've run over here down the hallway.
If you can see the rule 20.
Yes, I can see.
Well, I had handed off the.
Yeah, so the gem is in.
That's why Grygum has the red dots.
Okay, that's right.
Okay, cool.
I mean, I ran down there for a little bit, but I don't know.
Like, I don't know what to do.
So, could you place yourself where you think you are?
I would say, like, I'm around the corner, so I don't have line of sight to the back here.
All right.
Okay.
Hold on.
Should we just stop with that?
Thank you.
I feel like I had some sort of clever scheme for tricking people about the keys, but I can't remember what it was.
All right.
Okay.
So it's the thug's turn first.
So did we already do the acid damage on the thug for his turn?
No, I do not think we did it because he only we did the first round.
Does he take damage on his round?
He takes he takes damage at the start of each of his turns.
All right, so roll for his damage.
Yeah, let's roll two diaphragm.
Eight.
All right, he takes eight points of damage.
And let me see what the oh, they really got, they improved the.
Did you see how they improved the blood sprinkle?
Oh, okay.
So he can use an action to.
Yeah, I know.
Sorry, what did you say, Ben?
Sorry?
He can use an action to scrape it off.
Otherwise, it just keeps going.
Right.
He figures that if he doesn't.
This is a concentration spell, right?
It is.
So the bless ends, I guess.
Yeah, so the bless ends.
But since it's a concentration spell, he's going to.
What's he going to do?
Well, there's Thorn over there, and there's you, and you've got the.
All right, hold on.
Let's do a couple more things.
All right, I don't want to do them yet.
All right.
So the thug will just whack at Grygum.
Yeah, I was afraid of that.
Because that was like the most like, you know.
But I mean, he's got like really bad attack routine, so it's not going to be like today.
All right, that's a miss.
That's a miss.
You guys can see that, yep.
And that is another miss.
Both hits with the mace fail.
And
Ale Shites shits.
Shouts.
Don't go after Grygum.
Don't go after the cleric.
Go after the wizard.
The wizard's the one that we want.
He's got the key.
So.
Too late.
Hold on.
Two, three.
So, okay.
So both of you get an attack of opportunity against the thug.
Who's both of you?
Grygum and Thorin.
Oh, because he ran away?
Yeah.
Okay.
I mean, I'll take it.
Don't get me wrong.
In that case, I'll attack him with my mace.
That's a miss.
Did you do 17 points of damage?
No, that's if he's undead.
I did nine points of damage.
God damn it.
I assume his AC is higher than nine.
Yeah, yeah.
Just for the record, Dawnbringer is a she, we've decided canonically.
Yes.
It's going to be hard for me to remember that, but I will do my best.
And yes, I know.
Because my first girlfriend in high school was named Dawn.
Well, you know, that's how I'm going to remember it, just for the record.
I'm glad you said, I didn't want to share.
Oh, by the way, Gabe, we all fight, everybody finally learns you're married.
You've said it like 15 times.
I didn't know you were gay, dude.
And I'm like, it's like nothing like a group of dudes to be like, we've been playing for God knows how long.
And I'm like, who knew?
No.
Like, yeah, I was.
I just want you to know that we, I just wanted you to know.
I didn't think I was sharing anything, but apparently I was.
I mean, like, what abs, but also, who knew?
So for what it's worth, I have no, Christos, you have mentioned my husband several times in these sessions, but I guess it didn't register.
I didn't think it was a secret, so I just said it.
But yes, apparently it finally registered.
Isn't it?
I just wanted you to know, Gabe, so that you're aware of it.
I'm aware.
No, no, no, no, you're aware that you have right now.
Don't register these things.
That's my point.
We're a true guy group.
I just, that's the point.
I want you to understand that I didn't want you.
I wanted you to be part of the group.
Like, we don't register the important things.
Grygum, you missed, right?
Yeah.
Isn't Dawn canonically female?
I remember that from like the Iliad, like Rosiefinger, Dawn, that thing.
That whole thing.
I have no idea.
Okay.
All right.
So I need to do some initiative worlds.
So I'm ready, right?
It's my turn.
Yeah, just give me.
Yeah, give me a sec.
Give me one second, man.
Yes, I know you're ready.
Trying to figure out what that's going to be when I actually go to kick his ass.
All right.
I need a D20.
I have plenty of D20s.
Do I have an idea how many hit points the thug has?
Yeah, he's he's not a particular buff dude.
But
all right.
I don't know why it's different.
All right.
Okay.
So, first things first.
Why did it go to the thug three times in a row?
Oh, that's, I'm just,
I'm just, I have the combat gets more interesting in a second.
All right.
So, um,
so a couple things happened.
One is a Zentarim agent walks past Daz and the thug.
And actually, he just like wanders in like trumpeted debate.
What?
If he walks by me, don't I get an attack of opportunity?
Uh, yes, but he's also disengaging so nobody can attack him.
Okay.
So he seems very just let me walk you through what happens.
So he arrives in the room, he looks around, and LA Avonmore suddenly is in a state of panic.
What do they can we infer what they're in panic about?
Well, you are out of the room.
That's why I asked where you were.
So the other two, Grygum and Thorin.
And you could also try Glabbagool, Dave.
What do we roll?
Insight or invest insight or investigation, whichever one you want.
How do I roll for Glabbagool?
You roll a D20 and add his.
I got a six.
Yeah, I mean, if you roll.
Ooh, excellent.
With a plus nine, I got a 12.
Right.
All right.
Hold on.
Let's just tell him.
All right.
So, so he's freaked out.
Why is he freaked out, you might ask?
Okay.
Sorry, take it back.
That's not what happens.
Okay.
Sorry.
Take it back.
Okay.
Somebody is going to be upset later.
I had a premonition.
Yes, you did.
You did.
You did have a premonition.
All right.
Go for it.
First initiative.
Daz, you're us.
All right.
So I'm up.
I am going to miss the step my ass right here and then fireball the thug.
Okay.
He's dead.
Roll 8d6.
Roll a single d6?
No, 8d6.
8.
As in the number 8.
For my fireball?
Yeah.
Can I just click the.
Yeah, yeah.
I'm just.
I'm sorry.
I'm just like looking at how many hit points he has left and I'm just going, if you don't kill him, this is going to be epic.
Actually, no, you'd have to do, you'd have to roll pretty well to kill him.
So roll.
It didn't work.
Oh, there it goes.
That seems wrong.
Yeah.
Zero.
I think what happened was you, well, whatever.
How about this?
Type R slash R8D6.
I'm about to try this and see what happens.
Zero.
I'm just going to give up on that.
Technology failed.
25.
Oh!
Oh, if he makes the saving throw, he survives by one hit point.
Oh.
All right.
So I think I have to roll a 17.
Oh, and he rolls a 17.
Oh.
Damn, damn, damn.
One hit point.
So what happens is the explosive fires rage.
Like you've now, like, everybody knows that there's a big fight going on on the high tower, right?
On the walkway of the high tower.
Do you think the fireball was a hint?
Yeah, yeah.
The fireball was.
But the more important point is the fireball actually works.
Yeah, because it normally should be muted by the protection thing.
So everybody's now going to know that basically it's like the dream where you're in school and you're in your underwear.
Yes.
Yeah.
Everybody is going to realize that the Candlekeep is now in its underwear and they don't have yeah, right.
So like the fact that the fireball even worked
is concerning.
Never mind.
And of course, you know, immediately happy about or running in.
You hear screaming.
You hear panic.
You hear the bell ringing.
Yeah.
And if you could, you would see people taking notes and preparing their monographs.
Because what do you do?
What do you do in a situation like this?
Why conduct the experiments you've been waiting years to?
You take notes.
Exactly.
All right.
All right, that's what you do.
Alegos over here and he kills the thug.
Kills the thug.
All right.
He goes, he pauses.
Like, this is kind of like, you know, you're getting the impression that this guy's an interesting character.
By the way, Zalthir, Baba Gold's initiative, same as yours.
Just so that I don't couldn't, again, too many character sheets.
All right.
He suddenly stops.
And
I'd like to stop, but not surrender.
I'm aware how that sounds, and I have no reason to stop.
Just to time out for a moment.
Yeah, just time out for a moment.
Daz, roll your investigation.
Okay.
Everything's really delayed.
I might restart my browser.
No, for some reason, it's treating all your die rolls as zero, so you're going to have to add the D20 to it.
All right.
It's actually.
Did you maybe?
I get advantage.
So it's 21.
All right.
You notice that he's like listening towards the stairwell where you guys came up.
He's not looking at you, as if he's waiting, trying to see something.
He goes, I have nothing left.
I have nothing left.
You will have probably counted how many spells I've casted.
He pauses.
I'd be insulted if you hadn't.
I'm ticking him off on my fingers.
But I know which two lines of the cryptogram matter.
I know where the room under the keep is, and I know the name of the person in Menzoberranzan who has been paying to keep your drow breathing.
I would very much like to tell all of it to somebody with a locked door.
My fireball acts as a pretty good lock on this door way.
We can have the conversation now.
Okay.
Like, I don't trust anybody that's trying to delay and get us to go someplace else that they might lead us to someplace back.
I don't know what you guys think.
I mean, so what's your must have some kind of a hush spell or something?
He's like, he looks.
I mean, your investigation tells you this guy's not a murderer.
Like, this has got whatever plan, like, you know, he's one of these people who came up with a stupid plan and it went completely out of control and started to fall apart.
And he's like looking for a way out.
So he's scared of people overhearing the people who would want to kill him.
Yes, that's what you're getting.
Yeah.
And so the first thing you could ask is: what does he mean by a locked door?
Yeah, that is a good question.
Do you mean just behind in a place where it's hard to hear?
Or something more literal?
Would pardon me?
Do you go because in about four minutes, people will be coming up these stairs will be very disappointed in me, and you strike me as the more reasonable disappointment.
I mean, I'm assuming at some point somebody walks over to Daz and Zalthir and cures him.
So if you want to burn a heel spell, this would be the right time.
Yeah, I go ahead and how badly hurt is he?
He's at zero, so you probably fucked out.
Zero out of how much?
Zero.
Oh, God, the screen hides 57.
By the way, your ninth level.
Yes, I saw that.
That's exciting.
I don't know.
I don't know if I had to do anything.
No, nothing interesting at that level.
But thank you.
I just wanted you to be aware.
Okay, then I'll cast, it looks like healing word.
Did that roll?
Did it roll correctly?
Okay, there you go.
And let's see, where is he?
I have to go over and actually touch him for this.
LA kind of moves over here.
He still has the ability to cause like staggering amounts of damage, right?
Do not forget with his Cantrips.
Combat starts.
It starts at the top of the initiative order as before.
All right.
So he says, he looks at you and he says,
because in about four minutes, the people coming up those stairs will be very disappointed in me, and you strike me as the more reasonable disappointment.
And I figured that they might be reluctant to put me in prison, but I'm sure I could convince you would be willing to convince them to put me in prison in Candlekeep.
You realize that this guy's so much attached to the idea of being in Candlekeep that he'd prefer being in prison in Candlekeep.
Do we know anything about what prison is like in Candlekeep?
Yes, you do.
It's a place where spells can't be.
It's like the perfect place to be if you never want somebody with a large amount of magical power to get in.
Ah, okay.
This actually makes sense.
You know this because remember when you arrived, Kalan Strongbranch wanted to put the little drow in prison.
Ah.
And on the other hand, he's worried that the others would just want to kill him.
Is that it?
Well, I mean, you know, Kalan, Strongbranch, who knows who else?
Right?
The rest of the avowed.
Like, I mean, the guy was involved in a plot that involved lots of their peers dying, right?
He figures that you guys are not as emotionally attached to, you know, he did create a plot that resulted in the death of Janussi, the death of Bookworm, the death of Silvanus's son.
Yeah, he's a killer.
He's kind of, he's created an environment of mass murder.
So he's kind of like, you know, thinking if he's going to surrender, you guys are probably the best group to surrender to.
Safest for him.
Yeah.
Yes.
And he's not the I want to fight to the end kind of person.
And you also, you know, so he's sort of sitting there.
He's burned through all of his spells.
All right.
Let's place him under arrest.
So is that your call?
Place him under arrest?
Yeah, sure.
And then turn him over to the mercy of the council.
Okay.
So you like one of those movies where the bad guy actually convinces everybody to let him go and you just end up being pissed off and angry and then want to just kill him anyway.
I mean, the academic council, they'll.
Yes, he'll lose his academic privileges.
There's nothing worse.
Like, you know, he might lose his library card.
Oh, yes.
I mean, you know, or well, I mean, in Candlekeep, absolutely.
Right?
So who ties him up?
I mean, I literally have a feat for that.
Oh, you better do it.
Oh, right.
You do have a feat for tying people up.
Yeah.
What's that one called?
Something about street justice, I think it is.
Oh, really?
Okay.
It is, in fact, judicially tying people up, huh?
Yeah, certainly not.
Ben, I know what you're talking about.
I'm not playing that game.
Which game?
There's a Japanese, it's called Hojo Jutsu.
It's the way that they used to allegedly tie people up judicially during the samurai era.
That's not what he's talking about.
So, anyway, Christian, what should I roll?
My feet makes it hard to escape, but I don't know what to roll for taxes.
Whatever.
If it makes it hard to escape, then.
Oh, he's just standing there waiting for you guys to tie him up.
Okay, so he's tied up.
Yeah, no, I just, I mean, the fact that you're asking makes me think that he's going to try and escape, and it matters who actually ties him up.
That's why we're actually.
Why would you think that?
Because the statues always come alive and attack you.
Yeah.
And Thorin's looking at that.
And Daz, who's read the book carefully, is always looking at skeletons.
Yes.
You got to be aware and afraid of armed skeletons.
All right.
So here's what happens next.
Daz.
Did we lose?
No, no, no.
I'm just trying to.
Okay.
I'm just trying to run the combat here.
All right.
So.
Okay.
I did roll his initiative beforehand.
So there can be, it's just for the record.
All right.
So what happens is you're standing over there, right?
Yes.
Yeah, I popped out there.
Yeah.
You popped up there.
All right.
Said assassin appears now.
It's like one of those TV shows where there's all these like cameos of random ass people just showing up in the middle of the episode.
Yeah, yeah.
And an assassin?
Yes.
So an assassin, yes.
He goes, he's dressed in Zhentarim.
He looks, you know, the part, right?
Oh, okay.
Yeah.
He goes, Elias looks at him, holding his hands out like this, right?
You know, showing that he's been captured, right?
Goes, took your time.
They have had me since the landing.
And he points his, you know, he shows his hands.
It's not a loss.
It's a position.
I've been in the room.
I know exactly who is carrying what.
And he nod and he points to Daz.
So the assassin tries to kill Daz to grab the gem because that's who he thinks has the gem.
Of course, the assassin's about to be disappointed.
What?
So this one is the assassin and is now trying to kill me.
Is that what you said?
Yeah, yes, yes, because he thinks you have the gem.
Oh, by the way, like, I get to attack him then because, um, what is my thing?
He gets his first attack, then you get his life.
Let me just.
Yes, he wants the gem.
Well, he wants, yes.
I was just going to say, I wonder what the gem, because that's the gem where if you crush it or whatever, the thing comes to you, right?
Right.
So just because you have an amazing investigation.
Yes.
My passive investigation is 24.
So, so, so in these omnipotent.
Yeah.
And in these plot moments, I will share with you what's going on because Daz has figured all of this out by now.
And, but I think I'm going to start having to spin it conspiratorially just to fit your personality.
Okay.
I'll be like the dude from It's Always Sunny that's got the pictures and the wires.
Yeah, exactly.
All right.
Okay.
So what you figured out.
So just to be clear,
Elias thinks only an idiot would bring the second key to the room where he needs the second key.
Well, it's a good thing that, well, actually, sorry.
So he assumes that the key is somewhere in Candlekeep.
Okay.
And he probably thinks that whoever put it there probably didn't put it on somebody and hid it somewhere.
So he wants the sapphire to get the key.
The reason he was going to crush it was to get the key in his hand.
Okay.
Right?
So folks have been leaving.
Bad guys have been coming in.
It's entirely possible the key is not even here.
Right.
I mean, he, and if you, and even if you guys showed up and Tadric is here, right?
Remember Tadric, who had the keys, isn't dead?
He's figuring that you guys must have run straight here and dropped the key somewhere.
Because like you're too smart to bring both keys into the room.
Fair enough, but we don't have the room because we don't have the other key because we haven't crushed the thing yet.
Yeah, but you do have both keys.
Like the sapphire is as good as a key.
No, no, no.
You have both keys because Tadric gave Grygum the real key.
But I thought we had the key in a face.
But the sapphire is bound to, so we don't know where the other key is.
No, sorry.
I thought we had a real key, a fake key, and the sapphire.
Right.
And so the sapphire was Elias's way to find the key.
Which key?
The key.
Yes.
Okay, so the sapphire is basically dimensional loop.
It's just going to move from his left hand to his right hand.
Yes.
But here's the problem, right?
The reason he thinks that is because he thinks you're intelligent.
And you would never show up in the room where both keys were required by the evil bad guy, right?
You would have left the key somewhere else.
Well, then somebody could grab it.
I'm just telling you what he thought.
I notice what he's doing, and I pull out the fake key and toss it to him, saying, Did he already attack?
Wait, just before we go.
No, just trying to explain to you.
I'm just trying to tell you what Daz figures out.
Okay.
By the way, my guardian ability means that you can't disengage with me, so I would have been able to attack that assassin dude.
Well, he's right next to Daz.
He's right next to.
I know, but just like the turn when he went past me.
Oh, yeah, no, I got it.
I got it.
All right, just for the future.
Yep, he didn't have to do it this time.
All right.
And I did not know that when I placed him there.
So he thinks that Daz has the sapphire, which is how they get the key.
Okay.
Right.
But don't we don't actually have both of the real keys, right?
We don't we have a fake key and no, no, but Elias has one of the keys.
He killed Bookworm.
That's how he got one of the keys.
Okay.
Mizzik'do kills Bookworm, gets one of the keys, gives it to Elias.
Elias needs both key.
Elias has a real key.
Grygum has a real key.
Grygum has a fake key.
And Grygum has the, he can crush the thing, which we now think, I now think from my omnipotence that it will recall the key that he already has.
Yes.
Okay.
Right.
And so Elias thinks that you guys have stashed the key somewhere.
Okay.
Well, Grygum hasn't said anything about the key.
No, no, that's why Elias thinks what he's thinking.
Okay, good.
So there's two gems.
Each of us, only one gem, only one gem.
Okay.
But the gem is bound to the wrong key.
The gem is bound to the key that we already have.
Yes.
I get it.
All right.
So Elias was going to crush the gem because he thought that would get him the second key.
And then he had a whole master plan.
And then Daz used telekinesis and stole the key.
And now he's out.
Oh, stole the gem.
Stole the gem.
Which is as good as a key.
Right.
And that's why the assassin is about to try to kill Daz because he wants the gem.
But he didn't know that the gem was actually handed off to the person who also has the key.
Yes.
It's as clear as mud.
Yeah, I know.
I just wanted you guys to know.
I have the key and the gem that summons that key.
Yes.
Yes, you do.
All right.
So he attacks.
Who does he attack?
Daz, because he wants the damn key.
All right.
So he attacks with a, I mean, he does a lot of damage.
It's 20 points of damage.
And immediately after this, I get to attack.
Yeah.
All right.
Hold on.
I have to roll the hit.
I have an armor class.
No, no, no, no.
I just like, let me roll the hit.
Okay.
So this guy, apparently, they don't know how to do this anyway.
All right.
Okay.
So that's okay.
So, all right.
So the first attack's a hit, the second attack's a hit, and the third attack's a hit.
So you take a lot of damage.
How many hit points do you have?
Well, you said I took 20 points.
Wait, no, no, no.
I get to attack after the first attack.
Oh, okay.
Go for it.
I'm just saying, like, you know, we got to like, I may want to.
No, no, no, no, no, no.
How much did the first attack hit me?
Because I need to go ahead and record that.
All right.
Oh, shit.
I did really crappy, so don't listen to that.
So, what's his armor class?
Oh, that's the problem.
All right.
Let me just do it all over again because this guy, I was doing it with all right.
His armor class is 16.
Yeah, I know this was a miss.
All right.
You missed.
How do I recode the 1D 0 C S greater than 1 C F greater than 0?
I have no idea what that means.
What?
Hover over the 11 that I got there.
Tell me how, like, decode that for me.
That does not sound, that does not look correct.
I mean, I can do it again, but I'm.
Yeah, yeah.
The dice, the derolling is the deroing is somehow broken.
I had to shift reload.
Yeah, shift reload.
I had to shift reload to get it to where, and then I did another thing and it worked correctly.
All right, let me do a re-that is essentially saying you rolled a zero.
I mean, I've been having shitty rolls this session, so yeah, I know, but that's not what happened.
All right, I'm gonna roll again because all right, that's it.
Now that looks like he wrote 13 points of damage, which probably I just want to like make him a little angry and see if he'll attack me instead.
No, no, he's got a job, he's got a job to do.
But now that you attacked him, I now need to know.
All right, so the first attack was a 18,
and the damage was 20 points of damage.
The second attack was total, it was 25, and the damage was 23.
How many hit points do you have, Daz?
I had, before all of this happened, I had 30.
All right, so the second attack
kills you, knocks you out.
So I'm to zero now.
Yes, you're to zero.
And do I do a death save now or later?
Yes, you do a death save now.
And of course, the roles are not working.
Why are the roles not?
There we go.
17.
So that's a success, right?
Yes.
Yes, that is a success.
That is a success.
I need three of those, and then I'm back to that.
Yeah, you need three of those.
Or someone needs to stabilize.
Okay.
So
it's just two.
One there.
All right.
Okay.
There's a death save there.
We'll put a one.
Okay.
So that's what happens with the assassin.
And then the assassin has one more attack, and he uses it on
that is an 18.
I think that hits, right?
I didn't hear who you said you used.
Oh, no, actually, he doesn't attack you.
He attacks Elias.
No, actually, he does none of the above.
He looks through Daz's body and discovers, much to his horror, that the gem is not there.
There you go.
And then he turns to Elias.
Elias now is in real panic.
All right.
Next person in the initiative order.
Daz, you're knocked out.
Roll a saving throw.
Roll another one?
Yes.
So it's a failure and a loss.
Just one.
Just the one.
Yeah, but I got.
I have a success from the first roll, and now I have a failure.
Okay.
Sorry.
Thorin, you're up.
You're at zero hit points?
Yes.
Okay.
I'll help with that.
The next one.
My first question is: I see two Glabbagools, which I'm okay with.
No, there's only one.
Okay.
I mean, I'm going to.
Apparently, if you hit him with a slicing attack, he splits because he's an ooze.
I mean, yeah, so Glabbagool.
I haven't figured out how we're going to play that.
Glabbagool.
Glabbagools.
Is the second half sentient or is it an unsentient?
I don't.
We're not going to experiment on our dear friend Glabbagool.
Yeah, okay.
All right, Thorin, you're up.
All right.
Were you attacking, just so I know?
Oh, by the way, fucking A, we should have remembered.
After my attack, where I actually hit him, he should have had, he should have had disadvantage on his next attack.
Yeah, he gets a plus 10 to hit a 12.
All right, so he would have, he would have.
No, no, but no, no, but let me just roll.
Let me just roll.
I'm just saying, like.
Okay, I did not roll a one.
Okay.
All right.
So.
That was just fair.
That's fair.
No, I mean, you never know what could happen.
Eight points of damage for my first roll.
All right.
You're hitting him for another eight?
Another 14 points of damage.
All right.
And then I'm going to do, I want to like juice it somehow.
Give me a second here.
I don't like how this shit's organized.
It's hard to find what's what.
So he gets disadvantaged on his next attack, by the way, but
I can do
I'm going to do menacing attack, which means that I do a superiority die, which is a 1d8.
So that adds another five, and then he has to do a
wisdom saving throw.
Blue it.
Now he's frightened.
Oh, I'm so badass.
Okay, now I'm going to use my action surge.
All right.
Action surge.
Okay.
Well, I'm going to use that to do a third attack on him, which is another 13 points of damage.
No, action surge is all of your action, all of your attacks.
It's another multi-attack.
Is it really?
Fucking A, really?
Yeah.
So is it 15 points of damage?
No, 13.
All right.
And then I get to do yet another, which is a critical hit for, God help me.
I don't even know.
15.
Total of one.
Oh, you killed him.
Fucking A.
I feel vindicated, even though I don't.
Like, that's what you get for taking out one of my.
Not what I was expecting.
So, wait, I just want to see like critical hit damage, tinko combined.
But the rate, so this is radiant against.
I just want to make sure.
So, the radiant one hand was 12 plus 6.
So, I think that should have been 18.
Yeah, 18 or 23.
How much damage?
I'm trying to read this.
Okay, so wait.
So, let's do it.
Total combined one.
Okay, so total one-handed damage, total critical damage.
Wait, total one-handed.
Okay, so here's 12.
So, the six is doubled, so it ends up being 12 plus 6, which is 18.
So, 18 points of damage?
Is that how much?
Yeah.
Ah, he's still, you know, he has five hit points.
Sorry about that.
Okay, so he's hanging on.
Wait, let me see if I can do anything else.
Give me a second here.
I'm looking to see what I can do.
I just love the visual.
I'm sorry.
I'm just like pounding him.
Yeah, I mean, this is Zalthir level pounding.
I'm going to do.
I can do another 1d6 with Hail Strike.
All right.
So that takes him out.
Oh, wow.
You knocked him out.
Okay.
All right.
Elias is now really in a bad shape.
He thought the assassin was going to free him.
He's just betrayed you.
He's got his hands tied.
What do you guys want to do?
Well, one of us is down, right?
Yes, yes.
So I'm assuming you're rushing to go heal.
All right.
And I searched the body of the assassin to see if he has anything good because, like, you know, he's, you know.
So what's your healing?
How many?
What's your hit point, Max?
My hit points total is.
Oh, I can't see it anymore because I got to click this thing.
Yeah, click into the death time.
56.
Okay.
Let's use this one.
Is it rolling?
All right.
You're alive.
Why is it not rolling?
All right.
I'm alive again.
I will.
Oh, there we go.
40.
Thank you very much.
You're right.
And does anybody else need any more?
I wouldn't mind more.
All right.
Hold on.
We'll do.
How many are you short?
One round.
This is one round.
You can do one round of one round worth of healing.
So you can.
Okay.
Well, then I did it.
All right.
Just so we can keep otherwise, we're going to.
We do have some.
Some of us can be incredibly concentrated for my head.
All right.
Now, Elias kind of like looking very panicked right now.
Does anybody want to ask him why he's looking very panicked?
I mean, the obvious reason, Daz, is that he basically surrendered, then backstabbed you, and now is back to surrendering.
I mean, that's the obvious read.
Yeah, I don't trust this guy anymore.
Did you ever trust him?
Did we ever trust him?
So the question is: are we going to be good people and offer them up to justice?
Or are we going to just be like, solve the problem right here?
I feel like the cruelest thing to do would be to turn him over to the academic council.
So I'm in favor of that.
I think, like, I mean, that's, I mean, that's Grygum's, you know, brought up in a cultured environment.
You know, he's learned from Bahamut the importance of learning and what happens when you don't have it.
So there's a certain spirituality in all that.
Is there any sort of like hoist him by his own petard type of thing?
Can we like, you know how like when the cops really want to fuck with a criminal, they like take him in and then they like make it clear that he was talking to the cop so they think he's a snitch?
Can we do something like that?
Oh, where we like release him to the zentarum, but make the zentarum think that he was a snitch or something like that, so the zentarum takes care of the problem.
Yeah, so okay.
So yeah, we're going to do that.
I just feel like I'm chaotic neutral, and that feels like that would be.
You know, that I mean, you had the whole plan with Bookworm and he deprived you of that.
I know, right?
I wanted to work to hang him.
I feel like this is my nature to like try and like, you know, I think that's a, that's a, that's a, that's a, uh, that's a good thing to think.
You want to play good cleric, bad cleric with him?
Exactly.
All right.
So.
Can we like let Glabbagool have his way with him?
I mean, something like that.
Glabbagool's like, I've never eaten a vowed wizard.
What does the wizard taste like?
He's like, hmm, do they dissolve like other people?
I don't know.
We should find out, Glabbagool.
Alei is like, kick that thing away from me.
We could offer him a taste.
No, no, no, no, no.
That won't be necessary.
I mean, if you cut off, like, is there like, can you cut off like a wizard's fingers and then he can't wizard anymore?
I mean, like.
I thought it thought it was the heart.
I don't know.
The somatic parts.
I mean, but there's ways of working around that.
You know, you have to relearn your motion.
We're no longer ableists that way in edition.
Fair enough.
We were, just to be clear, we were.
A little bit of physical therapy.
Yeah, a little bit of physical liberty.
We have to relearn the movements, but you know, turns out it's the movement.
It's not the specific digit.
It's the movement.
You can do it in different ways.
Anyway.
All right.
So while you're doing that, Alei is, meanwhile, now Alei starts crying.
Okay, I have no sympathy for him.
Fuck him.
Right.
Yeah.
And he goes, you don't understand.
Explain it to us.
All right.
Do you want to stay in the room while he explains it to you, or do you want to leave the room?
That feels like a very loaded question.
That's like, you know, role for initiative type of question.
I mean, you know, just calling it a solid.
While we wait on Cassatas, were we doing something in this room?
Like, why were we here to begin with?
I think we saw, I think we were going to go into the tower.
So, we were afraid they were going to break into the tower and steal all the like super dangerous magic books.
The Glasya-Labolas Necronomicon.
Yeah, right.
Okay, so um, all right, so Alei so all right, so he's like freaked out now, very freaked out.
He lost,
yes.
Now, what so what is I'm going to give you a chance?
What would you like to do?
Do you want to stay in the in the in here?
And so, just to remind yourself, over here, the door, there is this door over here.
This door apparently opens into a room which has some kind of magical artifact
that is used, that you've heard is where that controls the security of the systems.
Okay, so that's the security control room, yes, security control room.
I mean, we know they've tempered with it because the security controls are partially deactivated, right?
Yes, well, with something else, who knows with what, but they don't have both keys, yes.
I say we get him out of the damn room before we start asking him questions, yeah.
Especially if we've got the keys that brings in hell and damnation.
Well, number one, we take the key off of him, right?
You now have both keys, yes, yes, but don't bring them together, okay.
And Grygum has one, who has the other key?
Just want to know.
So, I'm the one who takes it off him, but I slip it to Zalthir when nobody's looking.
Yeah, I think sticking in the middle of Glabbagool is probably not a bad idea.
Do you want to roll for Sleight of Hand?
Glabbagool, I mean, as long as Glabbagool, somebody tells Glabbagool to not talk about it.
Yeah, yeah, I mean, he's an awful lot of people.
You're going to give him a whole kind of love of silence.
Glabbagool's other name, Claude.
What?
Okay, so Zalthir.
Claude's not very good at following directions.
All right.
So, Zalthir also has the key.
Zalthir is very proud of himself.
He's feeling like he's now taking on important adventuring missions.
You mean Glabbagool?
Yeah, yeah, Glabbagool.
Sorry, Glabbagool is like, you know.
Oh, we handed it to Glabbagool.
Okay.
He gained a centimeter, you know, half a centimeter of height.
You know, the staying that two inches taller.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
That's cool.
Little less pancakey.
A little less pancakey.
All right, guys.
All right.
And yes, as you walk out of the room, you made the right choice.
So, what would have happened if he had sort of explained while we were in the room?
Well, I mean, bad things.
Yeah, I mean, the ultra-powerful wizard shows up and breaks the door.
Oh, I'm glad we didn't do that.
Right.
Cassatas, did you say you're away?
Yes.
We're going to play, though.
I'm going to be free.
I'm just going to wake up very early in the morning.
I appreciate your dedication.
Oh, dude, it's more fun.
Plus, it's jet lag.
So if for whatever reason, namely, I'm too drunk from the night before, I will send a text message.
But in that case, I might just decide screw it and not go to sleep and play.
Are you my daughter?
We appreciate your dedication.
No, no, no.
So, yes.
So, so, yes, Manshoon, the guy who's supposed to be dead, shows up.
And as he shows up, Alei enters the building.
Okay.
Right.
He casts a fire, a wall of force and then breaks the door.
The magic door that the keys actually protect?
Yes.
And, you know, at this point, you realize you realize the problem of the whole magical system, right?
So the whole struggle over the keys is moot because this is moot.
Sorry.
It's moot, because this dude could just show up and wave his hands.
Oh, yeah, but he would have showed up with a lot bigger power.
He's very much weakened as a result of that.
The reason he showed up.
Is there a spreadsheet involved?
Cassatas.
Yes, there was.
There was.
I mean, Manshoon wasn't going to show up, but you guys, but in the process of doing this, he managed to neutralize Alkhor.
Bookworm is dead.
I didn't say it was your fault.
Alei is captured.
Janussi is captured.
Kalan is to the wind.
And Manshoon has to expend massive amounts of magical power to get here.
So he's weakened.
But the whole point of the security of this place was that the avowed were supposed to be the final line of defense, but five of these wizards are out.
All right.
So he's taking a desperate gamble to get it, to get it.
It's so hard to find good help these days.
What, Gabe?
You look like you're.
I mean, wasn't the whole point we were trying to not have that happen?
Like, isn't it bad that he's now accessing or has access to the depository of items?
Well, that's where Alei says he doesn't.
Oh?
Yes, that was the detail he didn't tell Manshoon, which is why good that you didn't kill him.
But Alei is going to want something in exchange for that information.
All right.
Same bad time, same bad channel.
So, yeah, so just to be clear, in the original thing, Manshoon shows up with all of his goons fully powered.
All right.
So we fight a diminished Manshoon.
Yes.
You guys manage.
Now, all of his goons can't show up.
Only he can show up.
Secondly, you managed to capture Alei who knows what Manshoon is after, precisely.
So Manshoon is like, this is like the boss fight.
Yes.
Or the boss fight, yes.
So, yes, you did manage to diminish his arrival significantly.
Good.
Which is why Alei is so freaked out because Alei was like now realized, Alei was thinking there's no way Manshoon shows up.
Now Alei realizes that if Manshoon can show up in Candlekeep, Manshoon can find a way to show up in a cell inside of Candlekeep.
Yeah.
All right.
Hopefully, this all makes some amount of sense.
Yeah.
And so we have to figure out what we can offer Alei.
Yes.
I mean, at this point in time, offering him keeping them alive and not letting their previous boss get pissed off and kill them is probably enough.
Protecting him just long enough for all the wards to be placed.
You know, Manshoon probably burned a lot of magical artifacts to get here.
It was a one-time trip kind of thing.
All he has to do is survive long enough to not be killed.
Have none of the other avowed kill him,
right?
There's probably a whole bunch of people who want him dead.
Which ones are the avowed exactly?
That's the name of the Candlekeep.
The Candlekeep people.
The librarian.
Right.
Yes.
It's kind of like the clergy of Candlekeep are the avowed.
Gotcha.
All right.
Safe travels, Cassatas.
Thank you.
Thank you so much.
All the best.
Have a good week.
Take care.
See you later, sir.
Gabe, did you have a good time?
Yes.
Okay, good.
And now you know that your friends will know about your Dungeons and Dragons or professional things, but important details like who you're married to.
After years.
I think I still don't remember a name, but I know he's from Southeast Asia.
He's from Malaysia.
Chen is his name.
Chen.
Yes, which is why I was in Malaysia.
Makes sense.
It's like connection.
All right.
Have a good week, guys.
All right, man.
Have a good night.
We'll see you.
All right.
Bye.